[theme song in Japanese playing]
SPARKS OF TOMORROW
EPISODE 2: THE MYSTERIES OF THE CATALOG
[coughing]
- [Inako] Is that incense?
- [Kihachi] What's going on?
I found you at last,
my wife.
[screams]
- No! Not you!
- [groans]
I came for my darling wife!
And the 20th Century Electrical Catalog!
[gasps] Catalog?
Wha-wha-what do you mean?
- I'm not your wife!
- Just that. You are to be my wife.
[gasps] Your wife?
Wait, is this guy really your fiancé?
[Inako] Obviously not!
I have no idea what he's talking about.
Of course you don't.
It has only been a short time
since I received your father's blessing.
Look at you, so happy you can't speak.
I get it.
It's a great honor
to be betrothed to me, after all.
Yosuke Mizoe. The heir to the Mizoe Firm!
I refuse!
[Yosuke scoffs] What does that mean?
It almost sounds like
you don't want to be my wife.
I don't want to be your wife! I refuse!
- [yelps] What?
- [power sparks]
- I refuse!
- [whimpers]
[strained] Enough playing around.
- Give me the catalog!
- No! No!
- Let go!
- [straining]
- Hey! Knock it off! You'll tear it!
- [groaning]
[yelps]
- [crashing echoing]
- [inaudible]
[gasps]
Ugh! What are you doing,
you pompous creep?
- [grunting]
- [rattling]
[Kihachi] Get out of here!
[Yosuke] You're too late, kid!
[energy crackling]
- [gasps]
- [aide grunts]
Mr. Mizoe!
[Yosuke sighs]
What… [gulps]
- No, don't hurt him! [gasps]
- [aide] Sorry, Miss.
[Inari squeaks]
My hair's ruined!
[grumbling]
- Aah!
- [aide] Hmm.
[Yajiro gasps]
[whimpers softly]
Do not be alarmed.
[Yajiro] Kihachi!
[Bunshichi gasps]
Damn it! Who was that brat?
- If he's using electricity… [growls]
- What's the plan now?
- Sir, what should we do next?
- [yells] Aah! We're done here!
- Get me out of this place at once!
- [static crackles]
I've got you, K-K-Kihachi!
[groans] The catalog…
Did he get the catalog?
[grunts] Damn it!
- [engine revving]
- [steam hissing]
[lively music playing]
[grunting]
[Kihachi] Stop that car!
- [Yosuke yelps]
- [Inako groans]
[Yosuke] You don't know when to give up,
do you, Sparky?
[Kihachi] Give me the catalog,
you white-haired freak!
[creaking]
[both straining]
Mr. Sakamoto! Grab it! Here!
- [Yosuke] Know your place!
- [Inako gasps]
[yells]
Blunt force is all
your inventions are good for.
You'll never be half the man he was.
Hold on back there.
I'm giving it some steam.
[Yosuke] Do it!
[Kihachi gasps]
- [yelps]
- [Yosuke chuckles]
See ya around, kid.
Please stop the car and let me out.
That's enough.
As a wife of the Mizoe family,
you will cease this disgraceful behavior!
Or do you wish to bring more shame
to your family's name?
[Inako sighs]
[Kihachi struggling]
Damn it!
[sobs] Why did he have
to take the catalog?
- [people exclaiming]
- [man 1] A steam pipe burst!
[man 2] Quickly! We need to contact
the Mizoe firm and report it!
[man 3] Hey, hey! Out of the way!
I need to change routes.
There seems to be an accident ahead.
I don't care, just drive!
Damn it. [growls]
[Inako] Hmm.
[lively music continues]
[inhales]
[exhales]
So, Sparky's all grown up.
I never expected to see him again.
[chuckles]
[gasps happily]
More importantly…
- It's time. Give it to me!
- No!
[Yosuke] You will do as you're told.
Do not dare defy me!
Please don't come any closer.
- Or I swear I'll throw it!
- Stop this foolishness at once!
Gah! There's smoke in my eyes! [screams]
Mr. Mizoe! [grunts]
[gasps]
[aide sighs]
- [panting]
- [Kengo] Yosuke?
[Yosuke] No! The catalog!
- The catalog?
- [Yosuke groans] Get it!
Right!
- [sighs shakily]
- [music fades]
I'll go help them.
- [murmuring]
- [man 1] What do you think they're up to?
[man 2] Cooling off
from this heat, I'd say.
Sister-in-law,
please keep an eye on my darling girl.
You couldn't deliver it to Mr. Sakamoto?
[man 2] That's the right idea, fellas!
Keep it up!
[Bunshichi sighs]
Don't just sit there, Kihachi.
Help me clean this up.
Uh… Hey, are you okay, Kihachi?
[Kihachi sniffles]
That pompous jerk scared the hell
out of me, barging in like that.
[sobbing] And he took the catalog.
I had it, I finally had it.
[sobs] How could I
lose it again like that?
Kihachi.
So… now what?
[Kihachi] Damn it!
[sniffles]
I've always been a coward.
And now I always will be.
[all panting and wheezing]
I can't go on! [gasping]
- [aide] Mr. Mizoe!
- What?
[screaming]
[waterbirds calling]
[Noriko] Father!
How could you promise
to marry Inako to Yosuke?
[Mr. Momokawa] How can I refuse
the heir of the Mizoe firm?
Marrying Inako into the Mizoe family
will keep our debt collectors at bay.
Our sake brewery is
in danger of bankruptcy.
- What of our family legacy?
- [Noriko gasps]
[Mr. Momokawa]
Do you want to lose the brewery, Noriko?
Of course not. But that still doesn't
justify locking Inako in the storehouse.
Can you tell me you honestly believe
there is another family out there
who will accept Inako as a bride?
The girl can't even serve
a proper cup of tea.
[sighs]
[clattering]
[Mr. Momokawa] Regardless of how you feel,
daughters should obey their father's will.
Father, Inako is only 15 years old.
There is still so much
she has yet to learn and experience.
[Inari squeaking frantically]
[Kihachi yelps]
[squealing]
[shamisen playing]
- [Inari squeaks]
- Huh?
- [squeaks]
- [Inako] Hi, Inari.
[squeaks]
- [squeaking softly]
- Aw, thank you, Inari.
Father was very angry with me when
I told him I didn't wanna get married,
so he locked me in here.
I understand where he's coming from.
If things stay as they are, the brewery,
my mother's legacy, will collapse.
Inari, I know I can save everything
if I marry Mr. Mizoe. [sighs]
It's always been like this.
First, my father gets angry at me
for disobeying him,
then he locks me in the storeroom.
After a while,
he comes back and apologizes.
And after all that…
[Kihachi] Are you really
gonna marry that guy?
[Inako] Mr. Sakamoto?
[Kihachi grunts]
Mr. Sakamoto, why are you here?
Just call me Kihachi.
Kihachi?
You mentioned Momokawa Sake Brewery
in the recording yesterday,
so I figured you'd be here.
You can't be here! If anyone sees you,
you'll be in big trouble.
It's worth the risk. There's something
I need to know about the catalog.
Huh? Oh, that's perfect.
It's right here!
Huh? Wait. Didn't he try
to take that from you?
[Inako] He tried. But I hid it.
THE 20TH CENTURY ELECTRICAL CATALOG
[Kihachi] Um…
[Inako] Hmm!
[Yosuke panting and wheezing]
Izo! Kuga! Grab it!
[both yell]
[groaning]
Give it here! Hand it over!
Gah!
Huh? [gasps]
[Kengo] It's empty.
[Yosuke shudders]
My sweet darling girl,
what have you done now?
NUMBER 11
[Kihachi] There's no doubt.
This is definitely the catalog
my older brother gave me.
[wistful music playing]
- [Inako] Your brother gave this to you?
- [Seiroku] Kihachi.
[Kihachi] He said the 20th century
would be the Age of Electricity,
and to put all my ideas
for inventions in here.
Then he took me
to the Industrial Exhibition.
Ever since that day,
my head has been swimming
with all sorts of visions of the future.
NUMBER 2, ELECTRICITY
I can tell you really look up to your
big brother by how you talk about him.
[gasps and grunts]
He said we'd bring in
the Age of Electricity.
He took the catalog with him to war,
and never came back.
Can't believe I trusted him.
I'd never look up to someone like that.
But now you finally
have the catalog again!
- Don't take me for a fool.
- [gasps] I'm not… trying to.
You just show up out of the blue
and tell me your sister's
had this the whole time?
And it's been torn in half!
My brother went
to a vocational school in Shiga.
Where would he have even met your sister?
Okay, they knew each other, so what?
He knew her well enough
to entrust her with this?
What's that mean?
Are you trying to suggest
that my sister is being dishonest?
- No. But you gotta admit it's suspicious.
- You need to have a little faith!
Believing in one another
is what protects the bonds of humanity.
[Kihachi] Huh.
Whatever.
[scoffs] I'm out of here.
- [squeaking]
- [clattering]
Okay, bye.
You have to hurry. My father will be
coming back any minute to check on me
and I don't think
he'd be too happy finding you here.
[Kihachi grunting]
- It's… it's stuck!
- Hmm?
[Kihachi] Useless piece of crap! Damn it!
[groaning]
[Kihachi and Inako straining]
[squeaks]
[both groaning]
- [groans] I did it!
- [Inako sighs]
[both panting]
- You… only did it… because I helped you.
- [Kihachi yelps]
[both groan]
[Inako] I should… get back inside.
[wind gusting]
Sure you wanna do that?
[Inako] Huh?
I…
I have to go back and marry that man.
Do you actually want to marry him?
No.
But my father told me I have to.
- [Kihachi] Hey, Bug.
- Huh?
Come on.
[Inako] Huh?
[Kengo sighs] You've changed, Yosuke.
Since when did you start
wearing such flashy suits?
Save the reunion for later.
All right. At least tell me
why you want the catalog, then.
You really have no idea
what that book's true value is, do you?
What are you talking about?
[chuckles]
Izo! Hurry up!
[Inako] Wow!
Man, helping you
has been one hell of a distraction.
[gasps happily]
[wind gusting]
Kihachi?
- Uh…
- [Inako] Thank you for everything.
- [Noriko] Inako?
- [Mr. Momokawa] Hmm? Inako!
- Quick! Someone help!
- Father, I feel so dizzy!
- [both yelp]
- Oh, goodness.
- Noriko, get off of me.
- [Noriko whimpers]
[both struggling]
- Oh, no! Are you all right, Father?
- [Mr. Momokawa] Let me up! Hey!
Someone! Come quick!
- He's seen us! Kihachi, run.
- [Mr. Momokawa] Noriko, get off me!
[Inako] If he catches you,
you're in trouble.
- Inako, wait!
- [Noriko] Father!
- [Inako] What are you doing? What's that?
- It's a kite.
I can use it to fly away.
Wow! Can you really fly that?
[Kihachi] Theoretically, yes.
But if I'm being honest…
I doubt it'll work.
[Inako] What do you mean? You invented it!
I never thought I'd actually
have to use this thing.
- Get them down!
- My inventions aren't half as good as his.
It's not gonna fly.
- [determined music playing]
- [Kihachi gasping shakily]
- Hey! Stop! What are you doing?
- I believe in you!
- What? [wails]
- Here we go!
- [Inako yelling]
- Hey! No, no, no! Wait, wait! Stop!
We're gonna fall, Bug, stop!
We're gonna fall! No!
- Yah!
- What do you mean, "yah"? I said no! Stop!
[Inako panting]
Jump!
[man] Young miss!
[men yelp]
[Kihachi yelling]
[screaming]
- [grunting]
- Just look at them go, Father!
Get off of me!
Hey, what is that?
- Inako is flying.
- [gasps]
No way! I wanna see!
[Kinachi trembling]
We're above the smoke clouds.
- I can see all of Kyoto from up here!
- [laughs] It worked!
- We're actually flying!
- We're close enough to touch the clouds!
- Ah, it's beautiful!
- [sniffs]
[joyful music playing]
[Kihachi sniffling]
[wind whistling]
Yeah. It really is beautiful.
- It feels like we could go anywhere.
- Yeah.
[Inako] Hey, Kihachi,
can you see Mount Fuji over there?
[Kihachi] Mount Fuji?
[Inako] It feels like a dream.
I could fly up here forever--
[screams]
[both screaming]
[Izo] Ah!
Mr. Mizoe!
I have to close the kite.
There's no other way! Ready?
[Inako] Ready!
[grunting]
[both screaming]
- [Kihachi] On the count of three…
- [Inako] 'Kay!
[Kihachi] One, two, three!
[Inako squeals]
[silence]
[Inako and Kihachi screaming]
- [both yelping]
- [branches breaking]
- [Kihachi] Argh!
- [Inako] Ugh!
[both groan]
- [gasps] Are you okay?
- [Kihachi groans]
[gasps] Oh, gimme a break!
Is that Inako up ahead? What's going on?
That boy is kidnapping my fiancée!
He's trying to do what?
[yelling]
[Yosuke] Why did you stop? Circle around
and we'll attack from both sides!
[both panting]
[Inako yelps]
I think I sprained my ankle.
- [Kihachi] Lean on me!
- [Inako whimpers]
- [Kengo roars]
- [Inako gasps]
What's that?
You can't run from me, you filthy punk!
Give Inako back!
[Kihachi] Oh, that guy can't be human!
[Inako] My sister always says Kengo is
as strong and fast as a steam engine.
[Kihachi] He's a human train!
[Kengo yelling]]
[groans]
[sounds slow]
[mother gasps]
[cries]
- [Inako] Quick, this way.
- [Kihachi] Right.
- [yelps] I can't!
- Kihachi?
No, I can't go in there.
It's too dark. I'm afraid of the dark.
It didn't seem
to bother you in the storeroom.
That's because there was still plenty
of natural light in there. [whimpers]
- [Yosuke] Izo! They went this way!
- Huh?
Let's just go back.
[Inako] If we go back, they'll catch you.
- Kihachi.
- [whimpers]
[sighs shakily]
I'll lead the way. Take my hand.
Are you really not afraid of the dark?
I have nothing to fear, 'cause
the Great God Akubi is protecting me!
[Kihachi] Huh?
- [water drips]
- [yelps]
[gasps] They must be hiding in there.
Where is that kidnapping punk?
- [scoffs] The big idiot.
- [Kengo roaring]
Hurry up, Kuga! He's hiding her over here!
- Izo, lend him a hand, would you?
- Right!
- [groans]
- [clattering]
- [thud]
- [both gasp]
I think Kengo found us. We need to go!
[insects chirping]
We made it! [yelps]
[gasps]
You've proven to be
quite a handful, my darling.
Let her go!
I've got you now, you filthy kidnapper.
I didn't kidnap anyone!
No, Kengo, please! You don't understand!
What exactly are we misunderstanding here?
He did try to run off
with my fiancée, after all.
THE 20TH CENTURY ELECTRICAL CATALOG
- [dramatic music playing]
- [Yosuke and Kengo gasp]
[Kihachi gasps]
The 20th Century Electrical Catalog…
[Kihachi shrieks]
This belongs to me!
It's all I have left of my big brother
Seiroku, and I won't let you take it!
You're Seiroku's… brother?
That's right. I'm Kihachi Sakamoto.
Seiroku Sakamoto was my brother!
[snarls] I know precisely who you are.
- [gasps]
- [Yosuke] Izo!
- [Izo] Sir.
- [Yosuke] Let's go, darling.
[Kihachi whimpers]
- [rustling]
- [Inako] Kihachi!
Hey! Get your hands off me!
I must ask you to be still.
Hey! Put me down! I told you already,
that catalog is mine! Let go of me!
[sighs deeply]
[door slides open]
[Yosuke] Anyone home? Mr. Momokawa?
I've come to return my darling.
- Uh… Inako!
- Inako!
I'm okay, big sister. [winces]
- [Inari squeaking]
- [Noriko] Inako, you're injured!
[servant]Come with me, miss.
I will tend to your leg.
[Inako] Thank you, Tome.
- [thud]
- [Noriko and Inako] Huh?
[footsteps approach]
This is the man
who tried to kidnap your daughter.
[chuckles] I must admit,
he proved to be quite a handful.
[Mr. Momokawa] I don't understand.
How were you able to track him down?
[Yosuke] I suppose you could call it fate.
- [Noriko] Is that Kihachi Sakamoto?
- It is.
- Trust me, I'm as confused as you are.
- [yelps] Damn it!
[step creaks]
[Izo] Mr. Mizoe.
[gasps]
Mine at last.
You pompous jerk!
That belongs to me and you know it!
[scoffs] You can shout all you want.
[whispers] Seiroku.
At last, I will make our dream a reality.
Huh?
[gasps] Is this a joke?
THE 20TH CENTURY, A NEW ERA--
[Yosuke] No…
[breathing shakily]
This can't be the whole thing.
It's nonsense! It's… it's…
a bunch of kids' drawings!
[Seiroku] This catalog holds
incredible power.
It's a secret!
Impossible! This can't be it!
Oh, I see.
The real catalog must be…
[pages rustling]
- [Yosuke] I'm no fool!
- [both gasp]
[Yosuke panting] This is a fake!
[wheezing]
- [yells]
- [Kihachi gasps]
[Yosuke] I don't know how you did it,
but this catalog is a fake!
Where is the real one?
[Kihachi gasps]
["Soarin'" by Ginger Root playing]
[Kihachi] It's a fake?
♪ Looking up and within ♪
♪ To try and move forward ♪
♪ Get back what you gave in ♪
♪ To drag yourself in ♪
[lyrics in Japanese]
♪ Oh, I'll be waitin' ♪
♪ Look at how far we've come ♪
♪All together ♪
♪ Soarin' ♪
[lyrics in Japanese]
♪ When I'm with you ♪
♪ Somethin' tells me I'm gonna be alone ♪